## Nicky Liu

917-361-2328 | nickyliu91@gmail.com | github: NickyLiu91 | medium: @nickyliu91 | LinkedIn: NickyLiu91

#### **PROFILE**

Full stack web developer with a passion for psychology and user experience. With a background in philosophy and psychology I discovered web development through video games and my interest in user experience. I attended Flatiron school's full-stack web development course where I learned a variety of technologies, and am a teaching assistant and grader for Trilogy Education where I help grade and instruct similar courses. I look forward to being able to combine my background in psychology with my interest in software development to create engaging websites and great user experiences.

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## League of Cards - <a href="https://github.com/NickyLiu91/League">https://github.com/NickyLiu91/League</a> of Cards (Demo)

A card game featuring characters from League of Legends where you get cards, create decks, and fight a computer.

- Utilized Rails/PostgreSQL API backend to create a relational database between cards, decks, and accounts
- React frontend dynamically displays changes to background, text, cards, and field in response to user input
- Restructured frontend using Redux to store user account information so different aspects can be easily accessed, displayed, and modified as needed by various components as the player interacts with them
- Functional AI that will play by considering the current state of the field, the AI hand, and any potential combos

# Granblue Fantasy Gacha Simulator - <a href="https://github.com/NickyLiu91/GBF-Gacha-Simulator">https://github.com/NickyLiu91/GBF-Gacha-Simulator</a> (Demo)

A simulator for rolling on the gacha machine for the popular browser/mobile game Granblue Fantasy.

- Restructured backend API to Node.js/MongoDB from Rails/PostgreSQL since database contains non-related objects
- React frontend to activate a roll and cycle through results when corresponding buttons are clicked
- Employed Redux to store currency and results from rolls in global state so they can be displayed, and updated by several several different components without having to pass props

Mobile BlackJack - https://github.com/NickyLiu91/Mobile-Black-Jack (Demo)

Blackjack vs AI for iOS.

- ReactNative used since card games are simple, lightweight, and often played as a distraction on handheld devices
- Display cards on the field and in both players hands, as well as dynamically updates based on player and AI moves
- AI makes moves based on dealer rules and the player's visible cards while preferring a safe approach

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- JavaScript, React.js, Redux, React Native, Node.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, RESTful APIs, HTML, CSS, PHP, SCSS, AWS, Python, C#, Java

### WORK EXPERIENCE

Generation USA - Teaching Assistant, Fullstack Web Development, Borough of Manhattan Community College Mar 2022

- Handling administrative duties (i.e. setting up calendar schedules, scheduling appointments, taking care of registrations)
  - Grading homework and projects
  - Facilitating understanding of lesson plans and answering student questions

Trilogy Education - Teaching Assistant/Grader, Fullstack Web Development, Columbia University

Sep 2019

- Grading homework and projects
- Facilitating understanding of lesson plans and answering student questions

### Computer Programming Blogger, Medium

April 2019

- Publish instructional articles on how to use various programming technologies
- Writer for two publications, Future Vision (340 followers) and The Startup (470k followers)

Private Tutor April 2010 - Jan 2016

- Improved students' school and test grades through one-on-one tutoring with a focus on English and essay writing

Joshua Aronson's Psychology Research Lab - Research Assistant, New York University

Sep 2011 - Jan 2014

- Set up study foundations by synthesizing information focusing on education, learning, and academic achievement gaps
- Supported studies by designing flyers and questionnaires and entering, cleaning, coding and analyzing data

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School - New York, NY - December 2018

- 15 week immersive Full Stack Web Development program, SQL, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React.js

City College of New York - New York, NY - Web Design and Development Certificate - April 2018

New York University - New York, NY - Bachelor of Science in Psychology and Philosophy - May 2013

- Overall GPA: 3.757 (Cum Laude), Dean's List, Fall 2010 - 2013, Founder's Day Award - 2013, Psi Chi Honor Society